<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Generated by crowdin.com-->
<resources>
  <string name="app_name">Glucosio</string>
  <string name="action_settings">ตั้งค่า</string>
  <string name="action_feedback">ส่งคำติชม</string>
  <string name="tab_overview">ภาพรวม</string>
  <string name="tab_history">ประวัติ</string>
  <string name="tab_tips">เคล็ดลับ</string>
  <string name="title_activity_hello">สวัสดี</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_headline">สวัสดี</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_terms">เงื่อนไขการใช้</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_terms_accept">ฉันได้อ่านและยอมรับเงื่อนไขการใช้งาน</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_terms_full">The contents of the Glucosio website and apps, such as text, graphics, images, and other material (“Content”) are for informational purposes only. The content is not intended to be a substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment. We encourage Glucosio users to always seek the advice of your physician or other qualified health provider with any questions you may have regarding a medical condition. Never disregard professional medical advice or delay in seeking it because of something you have read on the Glucosio website or in our apps. The Glucosio Website, Blog, Wiki and other web browser accessible content (“Website”) should be used only for the purpose described above.\n Reliance on any information provided by Glucosio, Glucosio team members, volunteers and others appearing on the Website or in our apps is solely at your own risk.  The Site and the Content are provided on an “as is” basis.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_subhead">We just need a few quick things before getting you started.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_country">ประเทศ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_age">อายุ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_age_invalid">กรุณาระบุอายุที่ถูกต้อง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender">เพศ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_1">ชาย</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_2">หญิง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_3">อื่น ๆ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type">ชนิดของโรคเบาหวาน</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type_1">ชนิดที่ 1</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type_2">ชนิดที่ 2</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_preferred_unit">หน่วยที่ต้องการ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_share_data">แบ่งปันข้อมูลนิรนามเพิ่อการวิจัย</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_hint_settings">คุณสามารถเปลี่ยนการตั้งค่าเหล่านี้ในภายหลัง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_button_next">ถัดไป</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_button_start">เริ่มต้นใช้งาน</string>
  <string name="fragment_empty_text">ข้อมูลไม่เพียงพอ \n ป้อนข้อมูลของคุณที่นี่</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_title">เพิ่มค่าระดับน้ำตาลในเลือด</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_concentration">ความเข้มข้น</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_date">วันที่</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_time">เวลา</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_measured">วัดเมื่อ</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_1">ก่อนอาหารเช้า</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_2">หลังอาหารเช้า</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_3">ก่อนอาหารกลางวัน</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_4">หลังอาหารกลางวัน</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_5">ก่อนอาหารเย็น</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_6">หลังอาหารเย็น</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_7">ทั่วไป</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_8">ตรวจสอบอีกครั้ง</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_9">กลางคืน</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_10">อื่น ๆ</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_cancel">ยกเลิก</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_add">เพิ่ม</string>
  <string name="dialog_error2">กรุณาใส่ค่าถูกต้อง</string>
  <string name="dialog_error">กรุณากรอกข้อมูลให้ครบทุกรายการ</string>
  <string name="dialog_delete">ลบ</string>
  <string name="dialog_edit">แก้ไข</string>
  <string name="fragment_history_snackbar_text">ลบแล้ว 1 รายการ</string>
  <string name="fragment_history_snackbar_action">เลิกทำ</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_last_reading">ตรวจสอบครั้งล่าสุด:</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_trend">แนวโน้มช่วงเดือนที่ผ่านมา:</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_trend_positive">in range and healthy</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_selector_month">Month</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_selector_day">Day</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_selector_week">Week</string>
  <string-array name="fragment_overview_selector">
    <item>@string/fragment_overview_selector_day</item>
    <item>@string/fragment_overview_selector_week</item>
    <item>@string/fragment_overview_selector_month</item>
  </string-array>
  <string name="preferences_about">เกี่ยวกับ</string>
  <string name="preferences_version">เวอร์ชั่น</string>
  <string name="preferences_terms">เงื่อนไขการใช้งาน</string>
  <string name="glucose_reading_type">ชนิด</string>
  <string name="weight">น้ำหนัก</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_custom_type">Custom measurement category</string>
  <string-array name="tips_all">
    <item>กินอาหารสดหรือที่ไม่ผ่านการแปรรูปเพิ่มขึ้น เพื่อช่วยลดคาร์โบไฮเดรตและน้ำตาล</item>
    <item>อ่านฉลากโภชนาการบนภาชนะบรรจุอาหารและเครื่องดื่มในการควบคุมการบริโภคน้ำตาลและคาร์โบไฮเดรต</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอเป็นเนื้อปลาหรือเนื้อย่างที่ไม่ทาเนยหรือน้ำมัน</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอเป็นอาหารโซเดียมต่ำ</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน รับประทานในสัดส่วนเดียวกับที่รับประทานที่บ้าน หากเหลือก็นำกลับบ้าน</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน เลือกในสิ่งที่ปริมาณแคลอรี่ต่ำ เช่นสลัดผัก แม้ว่าจะไม่อยู่ในเมนู</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอเลือกเปลี่ยนเมนู เป็นต้นว่า แทนที่จะเป็นมันฝรั่งทอด ขอเป็นผักสลัด ถั่วลันเตาหรือบรอกโคลี่</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน สั่งอาหารที่ไม่ใช่ขนมปัง หรือของทอด</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอแยกซอสราดสลัดต่างหาก</item>
    <item>ชูการ์ฟรีไม่ได้หมายความว่าจะปราศจากน้ำตาล หากแต่มีน้ำตาลอยู่ 0.5 กรัม (g) ต่อหนึ่งหน่วยการบริโภค ดังนั้นพึงระวังไม่หลงระเริงไปกับสินค้าชูการ์ฟรี</item>
    <item>Moving toward a healthy weight helps control blood sugars. Your doctor, a dietitian, and a fitness trainer can get you started on a plan that will work for you.</item>
    <item>Checking your blood level and tracking it in an app like Glucosio twice a day will help you be aware of outcomes from food and lifestyle choices.</item>
    <item>ตรวจเลือดดูระดับ HbA1c เพื่อดูระดับน้ำตาลเฉลี่ยสะสมในเลือดในรอบไตรมาสที่ผ่านมา แพทย์ของคุณควรจะแนะนำว่าจะต้องตรวจดูระดับ HbA1c บ่อยเพียงใด</item>
    <item>Tracking how many carbohydrates you consume can be just as important as checking blood levels since carbohydrates influence blood glucose levels. Talk to your doctor or a dietician about carbohydrate intake.</item>
    <item>Controlling blood pressure, cholesterol, and triglyceride levels is important since diabetics are susceptible to heart disease.</item>
    <item>There are several diet approaches you can take to eating healthier and helping improve your diabetes outcomes. Seek advice from a dietician on what will work best for you and your budget.</item>
    <item>Working on getting regular exercise is especially important for those with diabetes and can help you maintain a healthy weight. Talk to your doctor about exercises that will be appropriate for you.</item>
    <item>Being sleep-deprived can make you eat more especially things like junk food and as a result can negatively impact your health. Be sure to get a good night sleep and consult a sleep specialist if you are having difficulty.</item>
    <item>Stress can have a negative impact on diabetes. Talk to your doctor or other health care professional about coping with stress.</item>
    <item>Visiting your doctor once a year and having regular communication throughout the year is important for diabetics to prevent any sudden onset of associated health problems.</item>
    <item>Take your medicine as prescribed by your doctor even small lapses in your medicine can impact your blood glucose level and cause other side effects. If having difficulty remembering ask your doctor about medication management and reminder options.</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="tips_all_age_plus_40">
    <item>Older diabetics may be at higher risk for health issues associated with diabetes. Talk to your doctor about how your age plays a role in your diabetes and what to watch for.</item>
    <item>Limit the amount of salt you use to cook food and that you add to meals after it has been cooked.</item>
  </string-array>
  <string name="assistant">ผู้ช่วย</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_update">อัพเดตเดี๋ยวนี้</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_ok">ได้ ฉันเข้าใจ</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_feedback">ส่งคำติชม</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_reading">ADD READING</string>
  <string name="assistant_weight_title">ปรับปรุงน้ำหนักของคุณ</string>
  <string name="assistant_weight_desc">Make sure to update your weight so Glucosio has the most accurate information.</string>
  <string name="assistant_research_title">Update your research opt-in</string>
  <string name="assistant_research_desc">You can always opt-in or opt-out of diabetes research sharing, but remember all data shared is entirely anonymous. We only share demographics and glucose level trends.</string>
  <string name="assistant_categories_title">Create categories</string>
  <string name="assistant_categories_desc">Glucosio comes with default categories for glucose input but you can create custom categories in settings to match your unique needs.</string>
  <string name="assistant_check_title">Check here often</string>
  <string name="assistant_check_desc">Glucosio assistant provides regular tips and will keep improving, so always check here for useful actions you can take to improve your Glucosio experience and for other useful tips.</string>
  <string name="assistant_feedback_title">ส่งคำติชม </string>
  <string name="assistant_feedback_desc">ในการที่จะช่วยให้เราปรับปรุง Glucosio หากคุณพบปัญหาทางเทคนิคหรือมีข้อเสนอแนะใด ๆ คุณสามารถส่งข้อมูลให้เราได้ในเมนูการตั้งค่า</string>
  <string name="assistant_reading_title">เพิ่มข้อมูล</string>
  <string name="assistant_reading_desc">ตรวจสอบให้แน่ใจว่าได้บันทึกระดับน้ำตาลกลูโคสเป็นประจำ เพื่อที่เราสามารถช่วยคุณติดตามระดับน้ำตาลกลูโคสตลอดเวลา</string>
  <string-array name="assistant_titles">
    <item>@string/assistant_feedback_title</item>
    <item>@string/assistant_reading_title</item>
    <item>@string/assistant_categories_title</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="assistant_descriptions">
    <item>@string/assistant_feedback_desc</item>
    <item>@string/assistant_reading_desc</item>
    <item>@string/assistant_categories_desc</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="assistant_actions">
    <item>@string/assistant_action_feedback</item>
    <item>@string/assistant_action_reading</item>
    <item>@string/assistant_action_try</item>
  </string-array>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_preferred_range">ช่วงที่ต้องการ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_preferred_range_4">ช่วงที่กำหนดเอง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_preferred_range_min">ค่าต่ำสุด</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_preferred_range_max">ค่าสูงสุด</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_try">TRY IT NOW</string>
</resources>
