<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Generated by crowdin.com-->
<!--
  ~ Copyright (C) 2016 Glucosio Foundation
  ~
  ~ This file is part of Glucosio.
  ~
  ~ Glucosio is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  ~ it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  ~ the Free Software Foundation, version 3.
  ~
  ~ Glucosio is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  ~ but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  ~ MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  ~ GNU General Public License for more details.
  ~
  ~ You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  ~ along with Glucosio.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
  ~
  ~
  -->
<resources>
  <string name="action_settings">تنظیمات</string>
  <string name="action_feedback">ارسال بازخورد</string>
  <string name="tab_overview">بررسی</string>
  <string name="tab_history">تاریخچه</string>
  <string name="tab_tips">نکات</string>
  <string name="title_activity_hello">سلام.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_headline">سلام.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_terms">شرایط استفاده.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_subhead">ما فقط به چند چیز کوچک قبل از شروع نیاز داریم.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_country">کشور</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_age">سن</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_age_invalid">لطفا سن درست را وارد کنید.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender">جنسیت</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_1">مرد</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_2">زن</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_3">دیگر</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type">نوع دیابت</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type_1">نوع ۱</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type_2">نوع۲</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_share_data">به اشتراک گذاشتن داده ها به صورت ناشناس جهت تحقیقات.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_hint_settings">شما می توانید این را بعدا در تنظیمات تغییر دهید.</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_button_next">بعدی</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_button_start">شروع به کار</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_title">وارد کردن سطح گلوکز(قند) خون</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_concentration">غلظت</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_date">تاریخ</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_time">زمان</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_measured">اندازه گیری شده</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_1">قبل صبحانه</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_2">بعد صبحانه</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_3">قبل از ناهار</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_4">بعد از ناهار</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_5">قبل از شام</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_6">بعد از شام</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_9">شب</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_cancel">لغو</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_add">اضافه</string>
  <string name="dialog_error2">لطفا یک مقدار معتبر وارد کنید.</string>
  <string name="dialog_error">لطفا تمامی بخش ها را پر کنید.</string>
  <string name="dialog_edit">ویرایش</string>
  <string name="dialog_delete">حذف</string>
  <string name="fragment_history_snackbar_action">برگردان</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_last_reading">اخرین بررسی:</string>
  <string name="preferences_about">درباره</string>
  <string name="preferences_version">نسخه</string>
  <string name="preferences_terms">شرایط استفاده</string>
  <string name="glucose_reading_type">نوع</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_custom_type">دسته سفارشی شده برای اندازه گیری</string>
  <string-array name="tips_all">
    <item>خوردن غذا های تازه و فراوری نشده برای کمک به کاهش مصرف کربوهیدارت و قند و شکر.</item>
    <item>Read the nutritional label on packaged foods and beverages to control sugar and carbohydrate intake.</item>
    <item>When eating out, ask for fish or meat broiled with no extra butter or oil.</item>
    <item>When eating out, ask if they have low sodium dishes.</item>
    <item>When eating out, eat the same portion sizes you would at home and take the leftovers to go.</item>
    <item>When eating out ask for low-calorie items, such as salad dressings, even if they\'re not on the menu.</item>
    <item>When eating out ask for substitutions. Instead of French fries, request a double order of a vegetable like salad, green beans or broccoli.</item>
    <item>When eating out, order foods that are not breaded or fried.</item>
    <item>When eating out ask for sauces, gravy and salad dressings "on the side."</item>
    <item>Sugar free doesn’t really mean sugar free. It means 0.5 grams (g) of sugar per serving, so be careful to not indulge in too many sugar free items.</item>
    <item>Moving toward a healthy weight helps control blood sugars. Your doctor, a dietitian, and a fitness trainer can get you started on a plan that will work for you.</item>
    <item>Checking your blood level and tracking it in an app like Glucosio twice a day will help you be aware of outcomes from food and lifestyle choices.</item>
    <item>Get HbA1c blood tests to find out your average blood sugar for the past 2 to 3 months. Your doctor should tell you how frequently this test will be needed to be performed.</item>
    <item>Tracking how many carbohydrates you consume can be just as important as checking blood levels since carbohydrates influence blood glucose levels. Talk to your doctor or a dietician about carbohydrate intake.</item>
    <item>Controlling blood pressure, cholesterol, and triglyceride levels is important since diabetics are susceptible to heart disease.</item>
    <item>There are several diet approaches you can take to eating healthier and helping improve your diabetes outcomes. Seek advice from a dietician on what will work best for you and your budget.</item>
    <item>Working on getting regular exercise is especially important for those with diabetes and can help you maintain a healthy weight. Talk to your doctor about exercises that will be appropriate for you.</item>
    <item>Being sleep-deprived can make you eat more especially things like junk food and as a result can negatively impact your health. Be sure to get a good night sleep and consult a sleep specialist if you are having difficulty.</item>
    <item>Stress can have a negative impact on diabetes. Talk to your doctor or other health care professional about coping with stress.</item>
    <item>Visiting your doctor once a year and having regular communication throughout the year is important for diabetics to prevent any sudden onset of associated health problems.</item>
    <item>Take your medicine as prescribed by your doctor even small lapses in your medicine can impact your blood glucose level and cause other side effects. If having difficulty remembering ask your doctor about medication management and reminder options.</item>
  </string-array>
  <string name="assistant">دستیار</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_update">بروزرسانی همین حالا</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_ok">متوجه شدم</string>
  <string name="assistant_weight_title">بروزرسانی وزن</string>
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Exercise Types -->
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Intro Strings -->
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Smart Assistant Strings -->
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Badges -->
  <!-- Food Entry Labels -->
  <!-- About Glucosio Strings -->
</resources>
