<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Generated by crowdin.com-->
<!--
  ~ Copyright (C) 2016 Glucosio Foundation
  ~
  ~ This file is part of Glucosio.
  ~
  ~ Glucosio is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  ~ it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  ~ the Free Software Foundation, version 3.
  ~
  ~ Glucosio is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  ~ but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  ~ MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  ~ GNU General Public License for more details.
  ~
  ~ You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  ~ along with Glucosio.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
  ~
  ~
  -->
<resources>
  <string name="action_settings">ตั้งค่า</string>
  <string name="action_feedback">ส่งคำติชม</string>
  <string name="action_invite">เชิญช่วนเพื่อน</string>
  <string name="tab_overview">ภาพรวม</string>
  <string name="tab_history">ประวัติ</string>
  <string name="tab_tips">เคล็ดลับ</string>
  <string name="title_activity_hello">สวัสดี</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_headline">สวัสดี</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_terms">เงื่อนไขการใช้</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_country">ประเทศ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_age">อายุ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_age_invalid">กรุณาระบุอายุที่ถูกต้อง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender">เพศ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_1">ชาย</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_2">หญิง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_gender_list_3">อื่น ๆ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type">ชนิดของโรคเบาหวาน</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type_1">ชนิดที่ 1</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_type_2">ชนิดที่ 2</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_diabetes_gdm">เบาหวานที่เกิดขึ้นขณะตั้งครรภ์</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_share_data">แบ่งปันข้อมูลนิรนามเพิ่อการวิจัย</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_hint_settings">คุณสามารถเปลี่ยนการตั้งค่าเหล่านี้ในภายหลัง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_button_next">ถัดไป</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_button_start">เริ่มต้นใช้งาน</string>
  <string name="fragment_empty_text">ข้อมูลไม่เพียงพอ \n ป้อนข้อมูลของคุณที่นี่</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_title">เพิ่มค่าระดับน้ำตาลในเลือด</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_concentration">ความเข้มข้น</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_date">วันที่</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_time">เวลา</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_measured">วัดเมื่อ</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_1">ก่อนอาหารเช้า</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_2">หลังอาหารเช้า</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_3">ก่อนอาหารกลางวัน</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_4">หลังอาหารกลางวัน</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_5">ก่อนอาหารเย็น</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_6">หลังอาหารเย็น</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_9">กลางคืน</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_11">ตรวจสอบอีกครั้ง</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_type_12">อื่น ๆ</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_cancel">ยกเลิก</string>
  <string name="dialog_add_add">เพิ่ม</string>
  <string name="dialog_error2">กรุณาใส่ค่าถูกต้อง</string>
  <string name="dialog_error">กรุณากรอกข้อมูลให้ครบทุกรายการ</string>
  <string name="dialog_edit">แก้ไข</string>
  <string name="dialog_delete">ลบ</string>
  <string name="fragment_history_snackbar_text">ลบแล้ว 1 รายการ</string>
  <string name="fragment_history_snackbar_action">เลิกทำ</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_last_reading">ตรวจสอบครั้งล่าสุด:</string>
  <string name="fragment_overview_trend">แนวโน้มช่วงเดือนที่ผ่านมา:</string>
  <string name="preferences_about">เกี่ยวกับ</string>
  <string name="preferences_version">เวอร์ชั่น</string>
  <string name="preferences_terms">เงื่อนไขการใช้งาน</string>
  <string name="glucose_reading_type">ชนิด</string>
  <string name="weight">น้ำหนัก</string>
  <string-array name="tips_all">
    <item>กินอาหารสดหรือที่ไม่ผ่านการแปรรูปเพิ่มขึ้น เพื่อช่วยลดคาร์โบไฮเดรตและน้ำตาล</item>
    <item>อ่านฉลากโภชนาการบนภาชนะบรรจุอาหารและเครื่องดื่มในการควบคุมการบริโภคน้ำตาลและคาร์โบไฮเดรต</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอเป็นเนื้อปลาหรือเนื้อย่างที่ไม่ทาเนยหรือน้ำมัน</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอเป็นอาหารโซเดียมต่ำ</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน รับประทานในสัดส่วนเดียวกับที่รับประทานที่บ้าน หากเหลือก็นำกลับบ้าน</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน เลือกในสิ่งที่ปริมาณแคลอรี่ต่ำ เช่นสลัดผัก แม้ว่าจะไม่อยู่ในเมนู</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอเลือกเปลี่ยนเมนู เป็นต้นว่า แทนที่จะเป็นมันฝรั่งทอด ขอเป็นผักสลัด ถั่วลันเตาหรือบรอกโคลี่</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน สั่งอาหารที่ไม่ใช่ขนมปัง หรือของทอด</item>
    <item>เมื่อรับประทานอาหารนอกบ้าน ขอแยกซอสราดสลัดต่างหาก</item>
    <item>ชูการ์ฟรีไม่ได้หมายความว่าจะปราศจากน้ำตาล หากแต่มีน้ำตาลอยู่ 0.5 กรัม (g) ต่อหนึ่งหน่วยการบริโภค ดังนั้นพึงระวังไม่หลงระเริงไปกับสินค้าชูการ์ฟรี</item>
    <item>Moving toward a healthy weight helps control blood sugars. Your doctor, a dietitian, and a fitness trainer can get you started on a plan that will work for you.</item>
    <item>Checking your blood level and tracking it in an app like Glucosio twice a day will help you be aware of outcomes from food and lifestyle choices.</item>
    <item>ตรวจเลือดดูระดับ HbA1c เพื่อดูระดับน้ำตาลเฉลี่ยสะสมในเลือดในรอบไตรมาสที่ผ่านมา แพทย์ของคุณควรจะแนะนำว่าจะต้องตรวจดูระดับ HbA1c บ่อยเพียงใด</item>
    <item>Tracking how many carbohydrates you consume can be just as important as checking blood levels since carbohydrates influence blood glucose levels. Talk to your doctor or a dietician about carbohydrate intake.</item>
    <item>Controlling blood pressure, cholesterol, and triglyceride levels is important since diabetics are susceptible to heart disease.</item>
    <item>There are several diet approaches you can take to eating healthier and helping improve your diabetes outcomes. Seek advice from a dietician on what will work best for you and your budget.</item>
    <item>Working on getting regular exercise is especially important for those with diabetes and can help you maintain a healthy weight. Talk to your doctor about exercises that will be appropriate for you.</item>
    <item>Being sleep-deprived can make you eat more especially things like junk food and as a result can negatively impact your health. Be sure to get a good night sleep and consult a sleep specialist if you are having difficulty.</item>
    <item>Stress can have a negative impact on diabetes. Talk to your doctor or other health care professional about coping with stress.</item>
    <item>Visiting your doctor once a year and having regular communication throughout the year is important for diabetics to prevent any sudden onset of associated health problems.</item>
    <item>Take your medicine as prescribed by your doctor even small lapses in your medicine can impact your blood glucose level and cause other side effects. If having difficulty remembering ask your doctor about medication management and reminder options.</item>
  </string-array>
  <string name="assistant">ผู้ช่วย</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_update">อัพเดตเดี๋ยวนี้</string>
  <string name="assistant_action_ok">ได้ ฉันเข้าใจ</string>
  <string name="assistant_weight_title">ปรับปรุงน้ำหนักของคุณ</string>
  <string name="assistant_feedback_desc">ในการที่จะช่วยให้เราปรับปรุง Glucosio หากคุณพบปัญหาทางเทคนิคหรือมีข้อเสนอแนะใด ๆ คุณสามารถส่งข้อมูลให้เราได้ในเมนูการตั้งค่า</string>
  <string name="assistant_reading_title">เพิ่มข้อมูล</string>
  <string name="assistant_reading_desc">ตรวจสอบให้แน่ใจว่าได้บันทึกระดับน้ำตาลกลูโคสเป็นประจำ เพื่อที่เราสามารถช่วยคุณติดตามระดับน้ำตาลกลูโคสตลอดเวลา</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_preferred_range">ช่วงที่ต้องการ</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_spinner_preferred_range_4">ช่วงที่กำหนดเอง</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_preferred_range_min">ค่าต่ำสุด</string>
  <string name="helloactivity_preferred_range_max">ค่าสูงสุด</string>
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Exercise Types -->
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Intro Strings -->
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Smart Assistant Strings -->
  <!-- Future Strings Baked In Early For l10n -->
  <!-- Badges -->
  <!-- Food Entry Labels -->
  <!-- About Glucosio Strings -->
  <string name="dialog_add_weight">น้ำหนัก</string>
</resources>
